Set sail for Muppet mayhem!
Muppet Treasure Island is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Brian Henson.
After telling the story of Flint's last journey to young Jim Hawkins, Billy Bones has a
heart attack and dies just as Jim and his friends are attacked by pirates.
The gang escapes into the town where they hire out a boat and crew to find the
hidden treasure, which was revealed by Bones before he died.
On their voyage across the seas, they soon find out that
not everyone on board can be trusted.
Long John Silver, played by Tim Curry.
Billy Bones, played by Billy Connolly.
Mrs. Bluveridge, played by Jennifer Saunders.
Jim Hawkins, played by Kevin Bishop.
The Great Gonzo / Dr. Bunsen Honeydew / Waldorf / Mudwell the
Mudbunny / Zoot (voice), played by Dave Goelz.
Kermit the Frog / Rizzo the Rat / Beaker (voice), played by Steve Whitmire.
Muppet Treasure Island is a 1996 American musical swashbuckler comedy film directed
by Brian Henson and the fifth theatrical film featuring the Muppets.
Adapted from the 1883 novel Treasure Island by Robert Louis Stevenson, similarly to its predecessor The Muppet
Christmas Carol (1992), the key roles were played by live-action actors, with the Muppets in supporting roles.
The film stars Muppet performers Dave Goelz, Steve Whitmire, Jerry Nelson, Kevin Clash, Bill Barretta, and Frank Oz in various
roles, as well as Tim Curry as Long John Silver and introducing Kevin Bishop in his film debut as Jim Hawkins.
The film was released in the United States on February 16,
1996, by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution.
It grossed $47 million worldwide.
It also received generally positive reviews from critics.
It is the second Muppets film to be produced by Walt Disney Pictures,
whose parent company would later acquire the Muppets in 2004.
The film explores themes of island, pirate gang,
puppet, treasure hunt, puppetry.
The tone is lighthearted.